PAULO BRUNO SERAFIM

Deep Reinforcement Learning Researcher | Software Developer

I like to solve challenging problems using my creativity, developing new solutions to relevant and nontrivial assignments. Throughout my experience on different academic projects, I became a person who not only loves solving problems through innovation but also enjoys writing about them.

SKILLS

C/C++ 9 years Object-Oriented and Data-Oriented C/C++

Computer Graphics CG, 3D Printing, Computational Geometry, and Geometric Modelling in OpenGL and Qt

Reinforcement Learning 3 years Deep Q-Networks projects in the environments ViZDoom, PySC2, OpenAl Gym, and GymRetro

Python 4 years ML projects with OpenCV and Numpy

Deep Learning 3 years TensorFlow and Keras in Python

Digital Image Processing 3 years OpenCV (C/C++ and Python) and Octave

KEY PUBLICATIONS

- A Novel Approach for Automatic Enhancement of Fingerprint Images via Deep Transfer Learning. IJCNN, 2020.
- Patent applied for a novel method to automatically create parametrized support structures for 3D printing. 2019.
- A Method based on Convolutional Neural Networks for Fingerprint Segmentation. IICNN. 2019.
- Evaluating competition in training of Deep Reinforcement Learning agents in First-Person Shooter games. SBGames, 2018.

LANGUAGES







FOLLOW



paulobruno.github.io



in linkedin.com/in/pbserafim



github.com/paulobruno

CONTACT



1100 Benjamim Brasil, Fortaleza, Brazil



+55 85 999 972 923



pbrunosousa@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Deep RL Researcher

Apr 2018 - Present

CRAb - Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Animation

Deep Reinforcement Learning researcher, working with autonomous game agents using TensorFlow and the environments ViZDoom, OpenAl Gym, PySC2, and Gym Retro. Started a subgroup focused on DRL applications, especially in games and character animation. Co-advisor of two undergraduate and one PhD candidate students. Currently working on competition and cooperation with multiagent DRL and analysis of agent performance under different views of the same environment.

Software Developer

Feb 2019 - Present

Instituto Atlântico

Working on R&D Computer Vision project for HP applying Deep Learning to problems of human segmentation and image matting (2020). Previously worked on R&D projects for HP Labs on 3D printing, applying computer graphics methods for surface and volumetric meshes using C/C++. Developed a new way to build voxelized support structures using algorithms of different areas, like Geometric Modelling and Image Processing, which generated a patent application (2019). Improvement of Genetic Algorithm heuristics applied to a Bin Packing Problem (2020).

Software Developer

May 2018 - Feb 2019

GREat - Group of Computer Networks, Software Engineering and Systems

Developed solutions for fingerprint minutiae extraction and matching using OpenCV focused on high performance (2018). Implemented a dataoriented C++ version of SourceAFIS, reducing runtime in about 90% (2018-2019). Started a side project using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) for Region of Interest (ROI) segmentation using TensorFlow, presented at IJCNN 2019. Worked on a project to apply fingerprint image enhancements using TensorFlow and OpenCV (2019-2020).

EDUCATION

MSc - Computer Science

Mar 2016 - Apr 2018

Federal University of Ceará (UFC)

Research on multi-agent competitive applications of Deep Q-Networks using the environment ViZDoom. Evaluation of autonomous agents in shooter and foraging scenarios (2016-2017). Quantitative analysis of the behaviors of autonomous agents in a competitive First-Person Shooter scenario using Python and TensorFlow (2017-2018).

BSc – Computer Science

Jan 2013 – Dec 2015

Federal University of Ceará (UFC) - Magna Cum Laude degree

Worked on hair animation projects using mass-spring systems and OpenGL (2013). Developed research on neuroevolution for autonomous game agents (2014-2015).